40. Bill Gates after Microsoft. Bill Gates is famous because of Microsoft,
the incredibly successful computer company he founded. But what he has done since he
left Microsoft may change the world even more. Bill Gates' personal fortune was huge, and
he thought he should give more of it to charity. Rather than give money to other charities,
he and his wife decided to create their own. They created the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation,
the Gates Foundation, in 1999. The Gates Foundation operates transparently, which means you can
see how it spends its money. The Gates Foundation has both global and American goals. In America,
it wants to increase opportunities for education and access to technology. Around the rest
of the world, it focuses on health care and poverty. The Gates Foundation uses business
techniques to try to end poverty. It is sometimes criticized for these techniques. It invests its
money in companies to earn more money. But critics say some companies it invests in at home actually
cause problems in the countries they are trying to help. The Gates Foundation also contributes
to very important causes around the world. It supports medical organizations that provide
vaccines to children, treat HIV-AIDS, and tackle problems like malaria and tuberculosis. It provides
money for developing farming in poor countries and helping after disasters like earthquakes. In the
United States, the Gates Foundation works to get the Internet to public libraries so everyone can
use it. It also provides money for scholarships for poor students and supports projects to improve
schools. Bill Gates is one of the richest people in the world. It is only right for him to use some
of his wealth to help other people. His foundation may help him use his money to make a serious impact
on poverty and disease.